<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blake Ruprecht&#39;s Home Page on Blake Ruprecht</title>
    <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blake Ruprecht&#39;s Home Page on Blake Ruprecht</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blakeruprecht.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Most Beautiful Formula in Math</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/eulers-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/eulers-identity/</guid>
      <description>Why is it so pretty?&#xA;$$ e^{i\pi} + 1 = 0 $$ $e$ is Euler&amp;rsquo;s number, the base of natural logarithms $i$ is the imaginary unit, which by definition satisfies $i^2 = -1$ $\pi$ is pi, the ratio of the circumference of a circle to its diameter Euler&amp;rsquo;s Identity is a special case of Euler&amp;rsquo;s formula evaluated for $x = \pi$: $$e^{ix} = \cos{x} + i\sin{x}$$ It is an especially beautiful result in math because it relates five fundamental numbers in mathematics ($0, 1, e, \pi, i$) with the three most common operators in math (addition, multiplication, exponentiation).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>Below is an incomplete catalog of the blogs and books that I love. They are generally sorted in order of passion, but that&amp;rsquo;s harder to do than it seems.&#xA;Blogs NOTE: I linked my favorite article from each blog.&#xA;mnmlist: by Leo Babauata, great blog about minimalism, this post really hits home for me. zen habits: also by Leo B., covers zen and applying it to life, e.g. having no goals is fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What research taught me</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/research/</guid>
      <description>I worked on the AI Risk problem with Derek Anderson @Mizzou (Columbia, MO) with the Center for Geospatial Intelligence, and we worked closely with the Naval Research Laboratory. Shoutout to Derek, Jim, Fred, Chris, Grant, Curt, Charlie, Bryce, Jeff, Matt, and many more who helped me along the way.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I do not love the bright sword for its sharpness, nor the arrow for its swiftness, nor the warrior for his glory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black and white thinking</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/drawings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/drawings/</guid>
      <description>Black ink on white paper, mostly.&#xA;Shadow is the big question with this medium &amp;ndash; how do you represent shades of gray?&#xA;You only have two colors, usually limited at the minimum in line thickness by the width of your pen nib (I typically use 0.5 mm).&#xA;You can use hasing, stippling, and other techniques to create texture and the appearance of shadow. The denser the ink in a given area, the darker the area will appear from afar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside-the-box thinking</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/woodwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/woodwork/</guid>
      <description>If you can build a box, you can build almost anything out of wood. Heck, a lot of the challenge in woodworking is making the most right right angles possible (yeah, you read that right).&#xA;I took shop in middle school and it taught me three things: how to not cut off my finger (unlike my teacher), how to sand for hours by hand, and how to build boxes.&#xA;For example, furniture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to build your own computer</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/build-your-own-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/build-your-own-computer/</guid>
      <description>Building a computer is a fun journey, especially with the plethora of YouTube tutorials at your fingertips, but the real challenge lies in ensuring your chosen components are compatible. Get this wrong and you may end up with a black screen or, worse, fried components. Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know about compatibility to avoid disaster.&#xA;Motherboard and CPU. Your motherboard is the cornerstone of your build. Think of it as the backbone that connects and supports all other components.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DCBS hot sauce recipe</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/dcbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/dcbs/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Ingredients&#xA;1/2 cup Cashews soaked 25 Habaneros roughly chopped 1 Yellow Bell Pepper roughly chopped 10 Garlic Cloves smashed 1 Onion roughly chopped 1/2 Lemon juiced Pantry Ingredients&#xA;1 quart White Vinegar 2 Tbsp Apple Cider Vinegar 2 Tbsp Maple Syrup 2 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Sesame Oil 4 tsp Mustard Powder 1 tsp Turmeric Powder Algorithm&#xA;Soak Cashews in water for 30 min Prep Habaneros, Yellow Bell Pepper, Garlic, Onion Saute Olive Oil, Onion, Garlic until softened Add Habaneros, Yellow Bell Pepper Add White Vinegar, Apple Cider Vinegar, Maple Syrup, Soy Sauce, Sesame Oil, Mustard Powder, Turmeric Powder Bring to a boil, then reduce to a simmer, simmer for 30-45 min (longer is less spicy) Taste and adjust for seasoning Blend in a food processor/blender Pour into sauce jars About Quantity: This makes a ton of hot sauce, like a big pots worth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perfectionism is tough to recognize</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/perfectionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/perfectionism/</guid>
      <description>What is it?&#xA;Procrastination Fear of failure leads to procrastination Creates a vicious cycle All-or-nothing thinking Strive for perfect or flawless, almost perfect is seen as a failure Focused only on results High achievers can enjoy the process of chasing a goal as much or more than the actual reaching of the goal itself. Conversely, perfectionists see the goal and nothing else. They’re so concerned with hitting the goal and avoiding failure that they can’t enjoy the process of growing and striving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My quest for the perfect bowl of Noodle Soup</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/noodle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/noodle-soup/</guid>
      <description>Holy shit, it&amp;rsquo;s all coming together. After watching Kung Fu Panda as a kid, I&amp;rsquo;ve been craving a delicious Asian nooodle-soup dish. Instant ramen is a good solution for $1 and a heart attack, but I want something fresh, wholesome, and delicious. Before this journey, ramen never did it for me, and other dishes like Pad Thai and Lo Mein just didn&amp;rsquo;t hit the spot.&#xA;I never liked Thai food, and I&amp;rsquo;m a serious food explorer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EV charger installation</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/ev-charger-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/ev-charger-install/</guid>
      <description>For the record, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend you install an EV charger yourself if you have no electrical experience. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely dangerous, and if you mess up, you can very easily catch your house on fire, or worse. However, it&amp;rsquo;s cool to at least now the process in theory, and this way, you can see if your electrician is doing it properly as well.&#xA;How much does it cost? If it was free, everyone would do it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insect farming</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/insect-farming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/insect-farming/</guid>
      <description>I ate a scorpion in Bangkok and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good. The outer shell dominated the texture, and the meat tasted vaguely stale. Would not recommend.&#xA;I also ate grasshoppers, crickets, mealworms, and bamboo worms. I liked them all, and liked the mealworms so much I bought them many more times for a crunchy snack. They reminded me of a meatier cheese puff &amp;ndash; salty, crunchy, and airy. The crickets had much more substance to them, but were suprisingly good, with a roasted, fishy flavor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python scientific computing packages</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/python-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/python-packages/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done 5 years of science research and development using mainly Python, and have used the major scientific computing libraries. While this topic may seem intimidating, the actual usage of each library is typically pretty brief (a few lines of code), so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert in each library, you just need to generally know what they do so you can use them when you need to. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview with some of the most common code explained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install Python</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/python-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/python-install/</guid>
      <description>Python is the most useful general purpose programming language, probably because it is easy to use. Don&amp;rsquo;t let that fool you, it&amp;rsquo;s still difficult to get this anaconda up and running on your own computer.&#xA;Installation instructions Here&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;ll typically see, as concisely as possible. Bold terms are explained in the FAQ.&#xA;Download the latest version of Python from the official website for your operating system (Mac, Windows, Linux, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The terminal can do almost everything</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/terminal/</guid>
      <description>SUMMARY&#xA;Note: I use {curly brackets} to represent variables where you replace the text inside the brackets, and don&amp;rsquo;t type the brackets themselves. This is often used in documentation, but not explained, so be on the lookout. Note: I use code text to represent code that should be typed into the terminal command line. ls lists files; ls -la lists all files the long way cd changes directory, cd .. goes up one dir, cd {dir} takes you to the &amp;ldquo;dir&amp;rdquo; folder mv {dir1/old} {dir2/new} moves a file from the first dir position to the second dir position mv {dir1} {dir2} changes the name of the folder mkdir {dirname} creates a new directory touch {filename} creates a new empty file grep [options] pattern {files} searchs all the files in {files} for the &amp;ldquo;pattern&amp;rdquo; specified, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux, MacOS, and Windows are all good</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/os/</guid>
      <description>I recently posted about my Linux setup, and I&amp;rsquo;ve come to a shocking realization &amp;ndash; any OS is fine. Strengths and drawbacks, right?&#xA;Linux: Cost: FREE Ease of use: ADVANCED USERS, MOSTLY Coding: OTIMAL MacOS: Cost: EXPENSIVE (requires an expensive macbook) Ease of use: EASY TO USE Coding: EASY Windows: Cost: EXPENSIVE (requires a $100 license) Ease of use: FINE Coding: ANNOYING If you already have Windows, my recommendation is to just keep it until you get annoyed enough to need to switch, which could be never.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good computers to buy</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/computer-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/computer-hardware/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trained as a computer scientist, so technically I know nothing about computer hardware. That&amp;rsquo;s the domain of computer engineers. Still, I have a lot of experience with computers and can give some general recommendations. This is probably most applicable to people in the USA, but not too sure.&#xA;I recommend Apple Macbooks, Dell XPS 13s, and Lenovo Thinkpads in this article. There are many more good computers out there, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have personal experience with others, so I won&amp;rsquo;t recommend them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple software follows Unix principles</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/simple-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/simple-software/</guid>
      <description>Update 2024-09-27 Of course, I did this as a fun experiment to see if Linux was worth it. It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months of daily driving this setup on my computer, and I can confidently say that it works great. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll do it again, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll install Linux Mint next, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll go back to MacOS.&#xA;I appreciate being able to do this, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I ever personally want to dedicate the time to this much coding again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My memories are stored in melodies</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/melodic-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/melodic-memory/</guid>
      <description>The greatest distance between two places is through time. When I listen to music, occasionally a song will play that instantly transports me back to a specific moment in time, filling me with vivid memories of a moment I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget. When I play through these songs, I relive moments like they just happened.&#xA;Somewhere in the Middle One moment, it&amp;rsquo;s a hot and humid day somewhere in the middle of a damp Missouri summer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Something I should say more</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/ily/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/ily/</guid>
      <description>The tattoo on my achilles heel is an X. If you squint, it kind of looks like an intersection, or a crossroad. To me, this represents indecision, my biggest weakness, and the thing I regret most in life &amp;ndash; not taking action to pursue love over fear. As I sit here at another crossroad, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think of the lyrics from the song that inspired the ink:&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the crossroad,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onebag travel is the way to go</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/onebag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/onebag/</guid>
      <description>Since I became an adult, I&amp;rsquo;ve always set out to travel with just one backpack so I never have to wait at that stupid baggage carousel thing. It&amp;rsquo;s never been a problem.&#xA;I recently completed a four month trip around Southeast Asia and Europe lasting from February through June. Prior to this, I traveled around the USA pretty extensively for some months. I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled a lot over the past few years, but this was by far the most travel I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done in a one-year period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Theory calculates optimal strategies</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/game-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/game-theory/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Intelligence is the ability to get what you want.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;As agents, we set goals and figure out how to achieve them. That&amp;rsquo;s what being smart is. Being intelligent is not the ability to learn 100 digits of Pi. That&amp;rsquo;s just pure computation. Being intelligent is reciting those digits to a girl you have a crush on, but only if it works. If she gets the ick, then that behavior was dumb, unless you were purely competing with yourself, in which case it&amp;rsquo;s back to being smart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Change your mindset to prioritize growth by praising yourself for effort, hard-work, and learning. Talk to yourself like a friend, don&amp;rsquo;t try to be perfect, and engage in positive self-talk. Eventually, you will be making more progress than you ever were with a fixed mindset.&#xA;Growth mindset is when you believe you can improve at anything with time and effort. Instead of seeing challenges as an internal problem, you see them as a chance to get better and improve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make cold brew</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/cold-brew/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/cold-brew/</guid>
      <description>I normally pay \$5-6 for cold brew out at a coffee shop. That&amp;rsquo;s about \$0.45/oz of coffee! I&amp;rsquo;m all for supporting local business, but I am also a local business and need to support myself, so here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it at home. The secrets won&amp;rsquo;t surprise you!&#xA;The Process Gather ingredients and tools. The total cost for the tools should be less than $40. Two big jars and a metal filter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning paradigms</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/ml-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/ml-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>At the highest level, machines learn very similarly to how humans learn. Data is given to the neural network, and then the robot does some calculations and tests it&amp;rsquo;s performance against the environment.&#xA;Supervised Learning (SL) Data comes with labels. The network makes an initial random guess at what the labels should be. Then, it compares the guesses to the actual labels, and determines how off it was (total error). It updates the network according to this error.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LSTM units incorporate temporal data into NNs</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/lstm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/lstm/</guid>
      <description>Utilizes temporal data, aka LSTM units can use previous information in their determination of current state.&#xA;The first sigmoid is the &amp;ldquo;forget-gate&amp;rdquo; $f_t$, the second sigmoid is the &amp;ldquo;input-gate&amp;rdquo;, $i_t$, the tanh is the &amp;ldquo;cell-update&amp;rdquo;, $\tilde{C}_t$. Forget-gate will determine how much of the previous cell-state we need to remember, input-gate determines how much of the new cell-state we need to remember, and cell-update gate normalizes the cell-state between [-1,1] because of the tanh.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ANFIS has gradient problems</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/anfis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/anfis/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Neural Network that incorporates Fuzzy Sets The first major project I worked on was coding up the Adaptive Neuro Fuzzy Inference System (ANFIS) in Python, specifically utilizing the PyTorch package to calculate the gradients. I calculated the gradients by hand to validate PyTorch, but wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you know it, PyTorch knows what it&amp;rsquo;s doing.&#xA;ANFIS is a type of artificial neural network that combines the antecedent and consequent logic (fuzzy IF-THEN rules) of fuzzy logic with the backpropagation learning techniques of multilayer perceptrons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reward drives behavior</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/reward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/reward/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s all about money. Or food.&#xA;Reward.&#xA;If you want to win a game, you should reward yourself only for winning. Not for time spent practicing, not for time spent reading, not for anything else besides winning. Don&amp;rsquo;t reward yourself for &amp;ldquo;playing hard&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;trying&amp;rdquo;, or for &amp;ldquo;having fun&amp;rdquo;, or doing one aspect of the game well. Sure, these tricks may be helpful to keep you playing, but they don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily help you win.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural gas learns a self-organizing map</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/neural-gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/neural-gas/</guid>
      <description>Similar to a Kohonen map, another self-organing map, but this time the topology is learned. Goal is to learn a topological structure to relate &amp;ldquo;close&amp;rdquo; datapoints to each other. Winner-takes-most. Growing neural gas starts with two-neurons and keeps adding a bisecting neuron until the stopping criteria is met (e.g. performance measure below threshold)&#xA;Algorithm Given an input dataset $x \in \mathbb{R}^n$ Init &amp;ldquo;weights&amp;rdquo; $w_i \in \mathbb{R}^n$ Pick a datapoint $v$ from $x$, For each weight $w_i$, calculate the distance to $v$ For each weight, determine the number (cardinality?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm to beat procrastination</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/procrastination/</guid>
      <description>$$ Motivation = \frac{Expectancy \cdot Value}{Impulsiveness \cdot Delay} $$ Step 1: Notice I&amp;rsquo;m procrastinating&#xA;I know I should do a task Step 2: Guess which unattacked part of the equation is causing me the most trouble.&#xA;Low Expectancy: am I likely to succeed? Is the task within my capabilities? Will I actually get the reward? Low Value: am I bored and distracted? Uncomfortable, onerous, or painful? Am I nervous or afraid of the outcome?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Choquet Integral generalizes metric functions</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/choquet-integral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/choquet-integral/</guid>
      <description>This is a really cool integral that basically maps any metric function on sets like the MAXIMUM, MINIMUM, MEDIAN&#xA;Choquet Integral: The Math Where $\pi(j)$ sorts the inputs based on their output values, $h_{\pi(j)}$, which is the output for input $x_j$. Little g is a measure such that $g(A) &lt; g(B)$ if $A \subseteq B$, $g(\emptyset) = 0$, $g(\mathbf{X}) = 1$. ChI adheres to monotonicity, idempotency, subcontinuity, etc. This includes the Linear Order Statistic (LOS) the Order Weighted Average (OWA), Maximum, Minimum, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multilayer Perceptrons are the basic unit of a NN</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/multilayer-perceptron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/multilayer-perceptron/</guid>
      <description>A type of NN that implements multiple layers of the basic perceptron.&#xA;$\mathbf{x}$ = input vector (e.g. $\mathbf{x}=[0.3, 5.4, 156.1]$) of length $N$ ($N=3$ in this e.g.), $\mathbf{x} \in [-\infty,\infty]$, can be normalized to [-1,1]$ or $[0,1]$&#xA;$\mathbf{w}$ = weight vector of length $N$ in the range $[0,1]$&#xA;$\sigma$ = activation function (typically ReLU, tanh, sigmoid, etc.)&#xA;$y$ = output scalar&#xA;$\hat{y}$ = label scalar&#xA;$e$ = error or loss function (typically Mean Squared Error as shown here)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks approximate any function</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/neural-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/neural-network/</guid>
      <description>Neural networks are universal function approximators, according to the Universal function approximation theorem. [[multilayer perceptrons]]. Neural Networks eventually got deeper and more sophisticated, becoming the single most useful tool for artificial intelligence.&#xA;Activation Functions ReLU TanH Sigmoid Loss Functions (1/2)e^2 Softmax $$ \sigma(z)_i = \frac{\exp{z_i}}{\Sigma_{j=1}^K \exp{z_j}} $$ $z$ is the input vector, $\in \{-\infty,\infty\}$, can be pos, neg, zero. $\exp{z}$ is applied to each element of the input vector, gives a pos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Flavor, 99 Calories</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/best-buds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/notes/best-buds/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to check, we might be out of Bud Select today, what do you want instead —- Bud Light?&amp;rdquo; No, you can&amp;rsquo;t replace the best type of Bud&amp;hellip;&#xA;It seems so impossible before it happens. You see it approaching. You see all of the warning signs, all of the speed bumps preparing you for the abrupt stop ahead. Somber stories are repeated from old friends who are long past the days of sitting on rooftops at 2pm on a Tuesday, skipping class and drinking cold ones out of a squat, plastic cup, deciding that their responsibilities can be pushed off for at least two more hours, until they hit that Ballmer peak of &amp;ldquo;creativity&amp;rdquo; or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to call drunkenly typing meandering lines of thought and utilizing spell check way too much and re-doing it all the next morning anyway &amp;ndash; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo Journal</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.com/photojournal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.com/photojournal/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
