<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blake Ruprecht</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blake Ruprecht</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Happiness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/happiness/</guid>
      <description>Setpoints The biological basis of human happiness is our neurochemical setpoints, which is the resting level of things like dopamine, serotonin, epinephrine, etc in the brain. They are mostly genetic and very hard to change.&#xA;If these are out of whack and making you unhappy, there are only three scientifically proven interventions to fix them:&#xA;Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy: The most highly regarded type of therapy which helps us identify our cognitive biases and distortions (untruths) and correct them to alter our brain chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/agent/</guid>
      <description>An agent is an active part of their environment. Action is something an agent does that changes the environment. Active - part of the environment that takes action (alive), e.g. humans, dogs, all animals and plants that do stuff. Passive - part of the environment that do nothing (dead), e.g. fire, stars, planets, moons, dirt, sand, water, air, etc. Agency refers to how active a part of the environment the agent is: something with high agency performs a lot of actions that change the environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Body language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/body-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/body-language/</guid>
      <description>A huge part of our real-life and video communication effectiveness comes down to body language.&#xA;Posture: Straight spine, head held high, open shoulders, neutral hips. Smile: Positive expression, look happy. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Character</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/character/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/character/</guid>
      <description>Your &amp;ldquo;being&amp;rdquo; or character is determined by what you repeatedly &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo;, or the actions you take. Character is the shape your entire being takes because of your habits. It&amp;rsquo;s the sum of your virtues and vices. It&amp;rsquo;s what you consistently are. Any action can become a virtue or a vice, depending on the thoughts and feelings that accompany the action.&#xA;What you say and do when nobody else is watching. What you fall back to under pressure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communicating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/communicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/communicating/</guid>
      <description>Communication is the process of transferring a message between agents. It is essential to coordinate action, trade, relationships, and survival. Almost every action of living requires interacting with other human beings. We acknowledge others with body language, spoken language, and written language.&#xA;The major forms of modern communication:&#xA;body-language: bodily expressions impact real-life and video chats talking: words spoken in real life, video chats, phone calls, etc. writing: words written in texts, emails, applications, websites, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/computing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;A computer is like a bicycle for the mind.&amp;rdquo; -Steve Jobs&#xA;Computing is powerful because it&amp;rsquo;s a direct extension of thinking. Just like language, it abstracts information into more easily transmittalbe forms to enable communication, the sharing of information from brain to brain.&#xA;Computing is all about understanding layers of abstraction. A computer is powerful because it&amp;rsquo;s not a fixed object, but rather a tool that changes itself through time, so it&amp;rsquo;s a process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cycling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cycling/</guid>
      <description>Cycling is the most efficient non-mechanized form of traveling for humans. A human with a bicycle is more efficient than:&#xA;A California Condor soaring through the sky A Horse running over the plains A Tuna fish swimming in the ocean The only required tool for cycling is a bicycle and whatever accessories you choose (e.g. a helmet, lock, etc.), or a different form of rolling around like a unicycle, tricycle, scooter, skateboard, rollerblade, etc, but these are all less efficient than a bicycle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/driving/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/driving/</guid>
      <description>The fastest form of personal travel and encompasses all powered vehicles piloted by yours truly, mainly cars, but also motorcycles, mopeds, e-bikes, scooters, etc.&#xA;Less efficient because it uses fossil fuels rather than human fuels.&#xA;Gasoline is maybe overall bad, unsure on this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/environment/</guid>
      <description>I am an agent in my environment, which is the entire universe (spacetime). My environment changes through time, which helps me orient myself in my environment. I can take action to change the environment. I can never know everything about the environment, instead a make a best guess based on my current state and trajectory.&#xA;A Glass of Wine &amp;ldquo;The whole universe fits into a glass of wine.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;If we split nature up into pieces to make discussion easier, nature does not know it!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fishing/</guid>
      <description>Tools required:&#xA;Hooks Line Fishing Pole Bait, Bobbers, Weights Net Clippers, Forceps Steps&#xA;Get a hook, and some string (aka fishing line) to tie the hook onto. Optionally, get a reel, a circle thing to wind the line around. Optionally, get a pole that holds the string and/or reel in place. Put some bait on the hook. You can use worms, hot dogs, grubs you pick up from the ground, bugs you catch, or artificial lures/flies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gaming/</guid>
      <description>Not really full on sports, but still competitive/cooperative activities which can provide all sorts of love.&#xA;Fun board games&#xA;Chess Texas Hold&amp;rsquo;em Fun video games&#xA;Smash Bros Mario Kart Minecraft Apex Legends Krunker Call of Duty: Black Ops </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/policy/</guid>
      <description>An agent&amp;rsquo;s predicted best course of action through time to get from the current state to a reward state.&#xA;The policy describes a future trajectory of state-action pairs which lead to a state in which the agent&amp;rsquo;s perceived reward is high.&#xA;A policy is an approximation, since any individual agent has an incomplete description of their state, as well as an incomplete memory, as well as incomplete knowledge of the environment to predict the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/predicting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/predicting/</guid>
      <description>My brain predicts the statistical association between state-action pairs and rewards gained from those states. It learns to associate state-action pairs with rewards that happen well into the future after said state-action pairs through statistical association. Basically, if a specific action in a specific state keeps leading to the reward, keep doing that action in that state.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public transportation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/public-transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/public-transportation/</guid>
      <description> Taxis - Uber, Lyft, call a taxi, usually somewhat expensive. Busses - Usually much cheaper Trains - Good in Europe, anywhere else if you can find them Boats - Pay for ferrying across water Airplanes - Expensive, only 20% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population has been on an airplane. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reward</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reward/</guid>
      <description>j- Reward is a state of an agent&amp;rsquo;s environment that produces positive thinking for that agent.&#xA;Rewarding states are the result of genetic factors, internal drives, thoughts, feelings, and emotions. Reward is different for every agent. Agents are ultimately the choosers of their actions, and they make choices based on what they predict will maximize reward based on their current sensations and understanding of the past. Related action </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sensing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sensing/</guid>
      <description>Sensing refers to the thinking processes agents use to detect changing states of their environment. As a human, I have external senses and internal senses which gather data about the state of my local environment. External sensing gathers state data about the environment &amp;ldquo;outside&amp;rdquo; of my body. Seeing: sensing the change in light/color levels around me, perceived as sight. Hearing: sensing the change in air pressure around me, perceived as sound.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talking/</guid>
      <description>Talking communicates information from brain to brain through spoken sounds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/</guid>
      <description>Tools are passive agents: parts of the environment that agents can use to perform actions faster. Tools get better over time as technology improves. Technology refers to the collective cultural knowledge of how to make tools, and the existing tools that are required to make more specialized tools.&#xA;Humans perform actions on parts of the environment (resources, e.g. water, air, sunlight, sand, dirt, rocks, metals, plants e.g. trees, animals e.g. cows) in order to change what the environment looks like, creating new passive agents called tools in the process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trajectory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/trajectory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/trajectory/</guid>
      <description>A trajectory is a sequence/history of state-action-reward information about an agents personal experience in its environment. A trajectory can be thought of as the history of an agent, all of their lived experiences, their story, their memory, their past, their knowledge.&#xA;A trajectory is basically the facts about what actions were taken in what states, what new states the agent entered into, the next actions they took in that state, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/understanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/understanding/</guid>
      <description>Understanding is the thinking process of paying attention to relevant sensed information from the past and present. Memory is the stored history of past relevant trajectory information based on our understanding in the past. Attention is our ability to prioritize state-action information based on high/low reward signals. Our brains aren&amp;rsquo;t big enough to store every trajectory of experience into memory, so we choose to keep informatoin that is relevant, new, or surprising.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/walking/</guid>
      <description>The easiest, simplest form of human locomotion for travel, but less efficient than bicycling except for hiking. More relaxing and fun than cycling, but less efficient.&#xA;Related traveling running </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing communicates ideas and tells stories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing refers to physical pictures which represent our spoken language. These pictures take the form of letters and numbers, and a combination of these form words, which combine to form sentences and paragraphs, all of which is called text.&#xA;Writing communicates thoughts in the form of written information to share ideas from brain to brain.&#xA;What does writing do? A writer&amp;rsquo;s role can be understood in several ways, depending on the context and purpose of their work, but at the core, writers aim to communicate ideas, tell stories, and share information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial intelligence vs Biological intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ai-vs-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ai-vs-bi/</guid>
      <description>Can AI do everything that human brains can do? They used to be dumb, but now, they&amp;rsquo;re smarter than your average bear.&#xA;Are minds just machines capable of searching the state-space of a Turing machine?&#xA;Memory of past state-action histories.&#xA;Attention to relevant parts of the state-action space.&#xA;Learning to improve predictions of reward-maximizing action.&#xA;Acting in the environment through time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eating macronutrients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/eating-macronutrients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/eating-macronutrients/</guid>
      <description>Macronutrients refer to large chemical molecules which are the primary components of all the cells in our bodies. These molecules are composed of Carbon, Hydrogen, Oxygen, and more elements/atoms. These molecules all come in many different forms, but as a whole they are grouped into the following categories for ease of discussion and energy counting.&#xA;Macronutrients are the primary source of energy for the body, as well as the primary source of building material for the body (proteins, fats, and carbs form most of the cells of the body).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/humans/</guid>
      <description>Humans are the S-tier most successful creature to ever walk this planet. It&amp;rsquo;s not even close. We named ourselves Homo sapiens in Latin, mean &amp;ldquo;man the wise.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;In the Game of [[life]], experience has shown that the group of animals that wield sharp sticks and even sharper brains are literally the Greatest Of All Time species to walk this Earth.&#xA;Man evolved from other primates, and for a long time, there were other humanoids walking the Earth, like the Neanderthals, Denisovans, H.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/living/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/living/</guid>
      <description>Stop doing everything. Take a moment of inaction. Stop thinking&#xA;The process of acting in every moment until acting stops (death).&#xA;A living being is an agent capable of changing their environment through action. Non-agents are passive, which means they cannot change their environment.&#xA;Life is basically one long chain of actions from birth to death.&#xA;My Actions = My Life thinking - the bodily process of every agent that chooses action through time</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/singing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/singing/</guid>
      <description>Singing I can make music anywhere I go with my portable music-maker.&#xA;Four chords and the truth The only instrument I know how to play is the Ukulele.&#xA;Like a true uker, I know like four chords and just like strumming and singing.&#xA;![[ukulele-chords.png]]&#xA;Related dancing melodic-memory </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/thinking/</guid>
      <description>Thinking is a continuous bodily process that controls an agent, turning sensed input into chosen action. Thinking never stops; if it stops, action stops, and life ends. It involves: sensing raw info about the environment (biased by expected reward), which includes sensing info from other minds (e.g. communicating, reading) You can hack your brain to direct your unconscious ATTENTION to pay attention to whatever you want. Use you eyeballs to focus on something, vision is the easiest way to hack human attention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applying</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/applying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/applying/</guid>
      <description>Applying is a chance to communicate your skills, experience, education, and personality to a potential employer to see if there&amp;rsquo;s a good fit for a specific job.&#xA;Resumes A listing of your Personal Information (Name, Location, Phone Number, Email Address), and a brief description of your Skills, Experience, and Education.&#xA;Keep bullet points action-oriented, start them with a verb, and try to explain your impact quantitatively &amp;ndash; evidence speaks louder than assertions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/working/</guid>
      <description>Working refers to gathering resources from the environment (tools, skills, knowledge) in order to perform the other actions of living. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a meta-action that is done to support all the other actions.&#xA;laboring at jobs if you have one&#xA;craftsmen: merchants/sellers, designers/R&amp;amp;D, builders, maintenace, operators resources: farmers, loggers, miners, diggers, hunters bodies: nurses, doctors, surgeons, trainers structures: foundation, roads, carpentry, concrete, steel, fertilizers, plastics, pharmaceuticals systems: plumbing, electrical, hvac machines: roads, bicycles, cars, trains, planes government: legislative, executive/military, judicial, lawyers, accountants media: writers, journalists, podcasters, youtubers, tv-people, movie-people, porn-people, radio-people journalists: entertainers: musicians, athletes education/religion: teachers, staff applying to jobs if you want one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drink water to maintain hydration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/drinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/drinking/</guid>
      <description>Drink when you&amp;rsquo;re thirsty. There&amp;rsquo;s no official recommendation for volume since every bodies hydration needs are different based on age, local temperature and humidity, activity levels, how much you sweat, and more factors. Water Bottle. Carry one around with you to drink more water throughout the day. 32 oz/hour. That&amp;rsquo;s roughly a liter per hour, around the max a person can absorb in one hour. If your pee is clear, you are just expelling water that your body isn&amp;rsquo;t using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/eating/</guid>
      <description> Eat 1000 cal smoothie for breakfast between 7-8am Eat 1000 cal lunchbox for lunch between 10-3pm Eat 1000 cal of something from my menu for dinner between 5-9pm Related eating-calories eating-macronutrients eating-micronutrients eating-anabolic gathering cooking drinking hunting insect-protein </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dreams of the Back Country</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/yosemite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/yosemite/</guid>
      <description>Left from St. Louis, drove down Highway 44 towards SW Missouri.&#xA;Drove into Tulsa, OK and got gas. Kept driving towards Texas.&#xA;Stopped in Lubbock, Texas for some late afternoon coffee to keep on trucking.&#xA;Texas started getting real flat, real fast. And hot. It was the middle of August. We had all four windows down in the little faded gold sedan that was currently hurtling down the highway doing well over 90.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Play games outside</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/playing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/playing/</guid>
      <description>lifting running fighting hunting disc-golfing balling gaming dancing How to Win Games Play fair. Nobody likes playing with cheaters, and most of your opponents will probably be people from your community that you&amp;rsquo;ll face again. Either way, it&amp;rsquo;s just to play fair and respect the rules. Chill out a bit. Forget about every past failure. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about future failures. If you want to win, you can&amp;rsquo;t be stressing about winning, just focused on executing the next action to the best of your abilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Educated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/educated/</guid>
      <description>What makes WEIRD people so educated?&#xA;What changes from the [[civilization]] era? Emphasis on group education, going from the heroic intellectual feats of individuals (Plato, Descartes, Aquinas) who were all either rich fuckers who owned slaves and had time on their hands to devote to study, or they were monks who similarly had lots of time. Educating everyone means we get decentralized science and [[the-system]] - Systematic improvement of intellectual knowledge - Leads to systematic improvement of machines - Quickly develop steam power</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Doing Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/now/</guid>
      <description>Work&#xA;On the job hunt, it&amp;rsquo;s rough out there Searching for Writing/Teaching positions Writing this website and my substack as evidence of my skillz Living&#xA;Almost 1 year in Denver, CO, my first big city. I don&amp;rsquo;t like big cities very much. Playing lots of Disc Golf and slow-pitch Softball (OnlySlams!) Running 1-3 x per week, Lifting 1-3 x/week. 3 is the goal but life happens every week like clockwork) Cooking up some delicious snacks I recently learned how to Fly Fish </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Resume</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-cv/</guid>
      <description>Skills (Communication) Writing, Content Writing, Copywriting (Teaching) Tutoring, Seminars, Presentations (AI/ML) LLMs, NLP, CV, RL, Prompting, Neuro-Fuzzy (Data) Analysis, Visualization (Code) .md, .html, .css, .js, .py, .c, .m (Tools) Unix, Git, Hugo, SEO, SEMRush, Google Analytics, Shopify, Klaviyo, WordPress, PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy, ROS Experience Digital Marketing Specialist @ Labyrinth.digital, 2024-2025 Freelance AI Solutions Consultant, 2023-2024 Research Assistant @ University of Missouri, 2018-2023 Freelance Tutor, 2014-2018 Camp Counselor @ Babler WiLD, 2017 Education M.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civilizations outcompete barbarians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/civilization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/civilization/</guid>
      <description>Barbarian roots For most of human history, the Earth was not covered by political nations which controlled every patch of land, like they do now. The world domination by civilization was incomplete. Up until at least the 1500s AD, there were still huge swaths of territory controlled by nobody in particular. Sure, roving bands of hunter-gatherers controlled portions of territory, but with armies so small even the Roman Empire would blush.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural selection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/natural-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/natural-selection/</guid>
      <description>References On the Origin of Species by Charles Darwin in 1859. &amp;ldquo;It is not the strongest of the species that survives, not the most intelligent that survives. It is the one that is the most adaptable to change.&amp;rdquo; </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Bookshelf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>Below is an incomplete catalog of the blogs and books that I love. They are generally sorted in order of passion, but that&amp;rsquo;s harder to do than it seems.&#xA;Books The Sun Also Rises - Ernest Hemingway (fiction) The book where I finally got it. Hemingway takes you on this journey, and at no point tells you what to feel, but gives you all the raw material. What happens in this book?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What my AI safety research taught me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/</guid>
      <description>I worked on the AI Risk problem with Derek Anderson @Mizzou (Columbia, MO) with the Center for Geospatial Intelligence, and we worked closely with the Naval Research Laboratory. Shoutout to Derek, Jim, Fred, Chris, Grant, Curt, Charlie, Bryce, Jeff, Matt, and many more who helped me along the way.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I do not love the bright sword for its sharpness, nor the arrow for its swiftness, nor the warrior for his glory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black and White Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/drawing/</guid>
      <description>Black ink on white paper, mostly.&#xA;Shadow is the big question with this medium &amp;ndash; how do you represent shades of gray?&#xA;You only have two colors, usually limited at the minimum in line thickness by the width of your pen nib (I typically use 0.5 mm).&#xA;You can use hasing, stippling, and other techniques to create texture and the appearance of shadow. The denser the ink in a given area, the darker the area will appear from afar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Box Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/woodworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/woodworking/</guid>
      <description>If you can build a box, you can build almost anything out of wood. Heck, a lot of the challenge in woodworking is making the most right right angles possible (yeah, you read that right).&#xA;I took shop in middle school and it taught me three things: how to not cut off my finger (unlike my teacher), how to sand for hours by hand, and how to build boxes.&#xA;For example, furniture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DCBS hot sauce recipe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dcbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dcbs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients&#xA;1/2 cup Cashews soaked&#xA;25 Habaneros roughly chopped&#xA;1 Yellow Bell Pepper roughly chopped&#xA;10 Garlic Cloves smashed&#xA;1 Onion roughly chopped&#xA;1/2 Lemon juiced&#xA;1 quart White Vinegar&#xA;2 Tbsp Apple Cider Vinegar&#xA;2 Tbsp Maple Syrup&#xA;2 Tbsp Soy Sauce&#xA;2 Tbsp Olive Oil&#xA;1 Tbsp Sesame Oil&#xA;4 tsp Mustard Powder&#xA;1 tsp Turmeric Powder&#xA;Steps&#xA;Soak Cashews in water for 30 min Prep Habaneros, Yellow Bell Pepper, Garlic, Onion Saute Olive Oil, Onion, Garlic until softened Add Habaneros, Yellow Bell Pepper Add White Vinegar, Apple Cider Vinegar, Maple Syrup, Soy Sauce, Sesame Oil, Mustard Powder, Turmeric Powder Bring to a boil, then reduce to a simmer, simmer for 30-45 min (longer is less spicy) Taste and adjust for seasoning Blend in a food processor/blender Pour into sauce jars About Quantity: This makes a ton of hot sauce, like a big pots worth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perfectionism is tough to recognize</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/perfectionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/perfectionism/</guid>
      <description>What is it? Procrastination&#xA;Fear of failure leads to procrastination Creates a vicious cycle All-or-nothing thinking&#xA;Strive for perfect or flawless, almost perfect is seen as a failure Focused only on results High achievers can enjoy the process of chasing a goal as much or more than the actual reaching of the goal itself. Conversely, perfectionists see the goal and nothing else. They’re so concerned with hitting the goal and avoiding failure that they can’t enjoy the process of growing and striving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/simplicity/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The simple way really is the best way to do things.&amp;rdquo; -Nick Saban&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Nature prefers the shortest path from A to B&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Nature operates in the shortest way possible.&amp;rdquo; -Aristotle&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Scientists must use the simplest means of arriving at their results and exclude everything not perceived by the senses.&amp;rdquo; -Ernst Mach&#xA;&amp;ldquo;If a thing can be done adequately by means of one, it is superfluous to do it by means of several; for we observe that nature does not employ two instruments if one suffices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My quest for the perfect bowl of Noodle Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/noodle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/noodle-soup/</guid>
      <description>Holy shit, it&amp;rsquo;s all coming together. After watching Kung Fu Panda as a kid, I&amp;rsquo;ve been craving a delicious Asian nooodle-soup dish. Instant ramen is a good solution for $1 and a heart attack, but I want something fresh, wholesome, and delicious. Before this journey, ramen never did it for me, and other dishes like Pad Thai and Lo Mein just didn&amp;rsquo;t hit the spot.&#xA;I never liked Thai food, and I&amp;rsquo;m a serious food explorer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My quest for the perfect bowl of Noodle Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tantanmen-ramen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tantanmen-ramen/</guid>
      <description>Holy shit, it&amp;rsquo;s all coming together. After watching Kung Fu Panda as a kid, I&amp;rsquo;ve been craving a delicious Asian nooodle-soup dish. Instant ramen is a good solution for $1 and a heart attack, but I want something fresh, wholesome, and delicious. Before this journey, ramen never did it for me, and other dishes like Pad Thai and Lo Mein just didn&amp;rsquo;t hit the spot.&#xA;I never liked Thai food, and I&amp;rsquo;m a serious food explorer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Install an EV Charger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ev-charger-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ev-charger-install/</guid>
      <description>For the record, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend you install an EV charger yourself if you have no electrical experience. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely dangerous, and if you mess up, you can very easily catch your house on fire, or worse. However, it&amp;rsquo;s cool to at least now the process in theory, and this way, you can see if your electrician is doing it properly as well.&#xA;How much does it cost? If it was free, everyone would do it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insects are Sustainable Protein</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/insect-protein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/insect-protein/</guid>
      <description>I ate a scorpion in Bangkok and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good. The outer shell dominated the texture, and the meat tasted vaguely stale. Would not recommend.&#xA;I also ate grasshoppers, crickets, mealworms, and bamboo worms. I liked them all, and liked the mealworms so much I bought them many more times for a crunchy snack. They reminded me of a meatier cheese puff &amp;ndash; salty, crunchy, and airy. The crickets had much more substance to them, but were suprisingly good, with a roasted, fishy flavor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python scientific computing packages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/python-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/python-packages/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done 5 years of science research and development using mainly Python, and have used the major scientific computing libraries. While this topic may seem intimidating, the actual usage of each library is typically pretty brief (a few lines of code), so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert in each library, you just need to generally know what they do so you can use them when you need to. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview with some of the most common code explained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python install guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/python/</guid>
      <description>Python is the most useful general purpose programming language, probably because it is easy to use. It&amp;rsquo;s also the lingua franca of AI research, because it has awesome science packages for free.&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t let that fool you, it&amp;rsquo;s still difficult to get this anaconda up and running on your own computer.&#xA;Installation instructions Here&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;ll typically see, as concisely as possible. Bold terms are explained in the FAQ.&#xA;Download the latest version of Python from the official website for your operating system (Mac, Windows, Linux, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terminal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/terminal/</guid>
      <description>Once you&amp;rsquo;re logged into your computers os, the most useful program is the terminal, a text-based application/program that enables you to navigate the storage of your computer and manipulate files and run programs directly through the terminal.&#xA;The terminal is the single most useful application/program I&amp;rsquo;ve learned across Linux, Mac, and Windows. It enables you to search across your entire hard drive folder structure, as well as run code in any folder you wish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operating System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/os/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Have a program do one thing, do it completely, and don&amp;rsquo;t do other things.&amp;rdquo; -the Unix philosophy&#xA;The operating system is a piece of computer software that controls all of the main functions of the computer &amp;ndash; using the CPU and GPU to perform calculations, storing the results in RAM and Hard Drive memory, and displaying the results on screens and creating a feedback loop with the keyboard and mouse (or touchscreen).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computers are cheap now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/computer-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/computer-hardware/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trained as a computer scientist, so technically I know nothing about computer hardware. That&amp;rsquo;s the domain of computer engineers. Still, I have a lot of experience with computers and can give some general recommendations. This is probably most applicable to people in the USA, but not too sure.&#xA;Basically, I recommend that most people either buy a ~5 year old laptop, or build their own computer, and then install the Linux operating system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My memories are stored in melodies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/melodic-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/melodic-memory/</guid>
      <description>The greatest distance between two places is through time. When I listen to music, occasionally a song will play that instantly transports me back to a specific moment in time, filling me with vivid memories of a moment I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget. When I play through these songs, I relive moments like they just happened.&#xA;Somewhere in the Middle One moment, it&amp;rsquo;s a hot and humid day somewhere in the middle of a damp Missouri summer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Something I Should Say More</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ily/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ily/</guid>
      <description>The tattoo on my achilles heel is an X. If you squint, it kind of looks like an intersection, or a crossroad. To me, this represents indecision, my biggest weakness, and the thing I regret most in life &amp;ndash; not taking action to pursue love over fear. As I sit here at another crossroad, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think of the lyrics from the song that inspired the ink:&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the crossroad,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Theory calculates optimal strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/game-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/game-theory/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Intelligence is the ability to get what you want.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;As agents, we set goals and figure out how to achieve them. That&amp;rsquo;s what being smart is. Being intelligent is not the ability to learn 100 digits of Pi. That&amp;rsquo;s just pure computation. Being intelligent is reciting those digits to a girl you have a crush on, but only if it works. If she gets the ick, then that behavior was dumb, unless you were purely competing with yourself, in which case it&amp;rsquo;s back to being smart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growth mindset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>Summary: Change your mindset to prioritize growth by praising yourself for effort, hard-work, and learning. Talk to yourself like a friend, don&amp;rsquo;t try to be perfect, and engage in positive self-talk. Eventually, you will be making more progress than you ever were with a fixed mindset.&#xA;Growth mindset is when you believe you can improve at anything with time and effort. Instead of seeing challenges as an internal problem, you see them as a chance to get better and improve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building computers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/building-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/building-computers/</guid>
      <description>You can build your own computer. If you need a powerful laptop, I can&amp;rsquo;t help you, I don&amp;rsquo;t know the meta anymore. If you want to use a desktop, do it, since you can build your own and upgrade parts as they break, rather than having to get a whole new computer every 10 years. It&amp;rsquo;s no harder than putting together a LEGO set. Watch a tutorial or three on Youtube and you&amp;rsquo;ll be fine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;How to Brew Cold-Brew Coffee&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cold-brew/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cold-brew/</guid>
      <description>I normally pay \$5-6 for cold brew out at a coffee shop. That&amp;rsquo;s about \$0.45/oz of coffee! I&amp;rsquo;m all for supporting local business, but I am also a local business and need to support myself, so here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it at home. The secrets won&amp;rsquo;t surprise you!&#xA;The Process Gather ingredients and tools. The total cost for the tools should be less than $40. Two big jars and a metal filter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/computers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a computer science master, so take these recommendations with a grain of salt. I&amp;rsquo;ve installed many different OSes, built my own computer, revived long-dormant old laptops, hand-built my own website, and coded in many different languages.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s my current computer setup:&#xA;Hardware: Dell XPS 13 9370 laptop, iPhone 13 Mini smartphone Operating System: Debian Linux (laptop), iOS 18 (phone) Programs: terminal, Firefox browser, Brave browser, Obsidian text editor, VSCode text editor, Cursor text editor, GIMP image editor, Zathura pdf viewer, Discord messaging Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (default for websites), Python (default on all Linux/MacOS machines), Go (for the Hugo SSG) I also have a smartphone (iPhone 13 Mini) running iOS 18 which I don&amp;rsquo;t use for any real computing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning paradigms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ml-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ml-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>At the highest level, machines learn very similarly to how humans learn. Data is given to the neural network, and then the robot does some calculations and tests it&amp;rsquo;s performance against the environment.&#xA;Supervised Learning (SL) Data comes with labels. The network makes an initial random guess at what the labels should be. Then, it compares the guesses to the actual labels, and determines how off it was (total error). It updates the network according to this error.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/action/</guid>
      <description>Action is something agents do to change their environment. It&amp;rsquo;s the only real thing we do. Thinking is the bodily process of choosing which action to take in every moment. To act is to live. Living is the process of taking action in every moment. When thinking/acting stops, we die. Sometimes we say we&amp;rsquo;re doing nothing, but we&amp;rsquo;re always doing some actions (e.g. breathing) until death. Your life is a string of actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reward drives behavior</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/reward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/reward/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s all about money. Or food.&#xA;Reward.&#xA;If you want to win a game, you should reward yourself only for winning. Not for time spent practicing, not for time spent reading, not for anything else besides winning. Don&amp;rsquo;t reward yourself for &amp;ldquo;playing hard&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;trying&amp;rdquo;, or for &amp;ldquo;having fun&amp;rdquo;, or doing one aspect of the game well. Sure, these tricks may be helpful to keep you playing, but they don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily help you win.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm to Beat Procrastination</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procrastination/</guid>
      <description>$$ Motivation = \frac{Expectancy \cdot Value}{Impulsiveness \cdot Delay} $$ Step 1: Notice I&amp;rsquo;m procrastinating I know I should do a task Step 2: Guess which unattacked part of the equation is causing me the most trouble. Low Expectancy: am I likely to succeed? Is the task within my capabilities? Will I actually get the reward? Low Value: am I bored and distracted? Uncomfortable, grumpy, or in pain? Am I nervous or afraid of the outcome?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/neural-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/neural-network/</guid>
      <description>Neural networks are universal function approximators, according to the Universal function approximation theorem. Neural Networks eventually got deeper and more sophisticated, becoming the single most useful tool for artificial intelligence.&#xA;The Perceptron (I&amp;rsquo;m just P), basically a straight line Similar to a brain neuron. The perceptron is basically a function that fits a straight-line relationship between a range of input values and some corresponding output values.&#xA;For example, to represent no relationship between input and output, you would have a neuron that outputs Y = 0 for every input value X.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Flavor, 99 Calories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/best-buds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/best-buds/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to check, we might be out of Bud Select today, what do you want instead — Bud Light?&amp;rdquo; -the waitress at Big 12&#xA;No, you can&amp;rsquo;t replace the best type of Bud&amp;hellip;&#xA;It seems so impossible before it happens. You see it approaching. You see all of the warning signs, all of the speed bumps preparing you for the abrupt stop ahead. Somber stories are repeated from old friends who are long past the days of sitting on rooftops at 2pm on a Tuesday, skipping class and drinking cold ones out of a squat, plastic cup, deciding that their responsibilities can be pushed off for at least two more hours, until they hit that Ballmer peak of &amp;ldquo;creativity&amp;rdquo; or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to call drunkenly typing meandering lines of thought and utilizing spell check way too much and re-doing it all the next morning anyway &amp;ndash; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4runned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/4runned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/4runned/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Stanley&amp;rdquo;, 2001 toyota 4runner limited (3rd gen), silver, purchased by Parents from Maternal Grandparents, stock, luxury packages &amp;ldquo;Ron&amp;rdquo;, 1997 (3rd gen) toyota 4runner (3rd gen), silver, blacked out windows, upgraded head unit, no muffler &amp;ndash; thing rode hard and fun Dad and I fixed the tension on the gas pedal in the other 4Runner. We had two of the same car for a while &amp;ndash; silver third gen toyoat 4runners.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decisive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/decisive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 1776 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/decisive/</guid>
      <description>AKA Drive, Thumos, Grit, Will, Gameness, Boldness, Bravery, Courage, Daring, Strength, Endurance, Dedication, Perservearance&#xA;Decisive = Choosing action despite fear. It’s the will to move forward in the face of death, uncertainty, or resistance. Fear is natural. It comes from mortality, the unknown, and opposition—but must be faced. Decisiveness is kinetic. It’s speed, energy, and the shrinking of the gap between thought and action. Time is precious. Courage means not wasting it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Present</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/present/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 1776 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/present/</guid>
      <description>AKA Flow, Balance, Acceptance, Temperance, Calm&#xA;Presence = Attention + Balance Love is attention. Where you place your awareness reveals what you value. Flow state = Happiness. Deep, undistracted engagement in meaningful action (&amp;ldquo;in the zone&amp;rdquo;) creates joy and satisfaction. Achieved by doing an action that is engaging (you enjoy it) and challenging Balance pain and pleasure to live a good life. Temperance = Disciplined Love. It&amp;rsquo;s not abstaining from stuff just for the sake of restraint or denial, discipline means fully committing to what you love so much, that you stop chasing every impulse that doesn&amp;rsquo;t serve your love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 1776 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rational/</guid>
      <description>AKA Prudence, Discernment&#xA;Wisdom = Right Action. It&amp;rsquo;s the ability to take the right action at the right time, based on experience, intelligence, and discernment of potential outcomes. Hierarchy: Knowledge → Intelligence → Wisdom → Action. Prudence = Applied Wisdom. It&amp;rsquo;s discerning what helps or hinders your goals (especially love or happiness) and choosing accordingly. Adaptability is key. Continuous thinking, learning, and changing beliefs are essential. Keep it simple. Efficiency and clarity matter (&amp;ldquo;shortest path,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;KISS,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;minimum is minimum for a reason&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/keep-the-wolves-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/keep-the-wolves-away/</guid>
      <description>I feel hot breath on my neck as I run forward, bogged down by mud and debris. One nips at my shoes, opening up a whole in the left side of the upper. Another snatches a hole in my pants. One up them knocks dirt into my mouth, a problem that will have to be professionally repaired. I lose my vision as my contacts fall out from running, I have to rely on my old glasses which restrict my peripherals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/religion/</guid>
      <description>Christianity&#xA;Epiousion: The New Testament was originally written in Koine Greek. Many mis-translations and errors in interpretation stem from people not knowing Koine. This word is a famous part of the Sermon on the Mount, specifically the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer. In the typical English translation, it&amp;rsquo;s part of the line &amp;ldquo;give us this day our daily bread&amp;rdquo;, and epiousion roughly translates to &amp;lsquo;daily bread,&amp;rsquo; but this doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell the whole story. I think back to this word all the time when I think about one of the key purposes of religion in general, and these teachings from Jesus in particular: have faith in the present moment, let go of your worries about your misgivings, and let go of your worries about future income (daily bread).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sharing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Build home, work, and third places&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/homes/</guid>
      <description>The two most important environments in most people&amp;rsquo;s lives are their home and workplace. Since labor is the predominant form of income generation for most people nowadays, travel is also mainly concerned with traveling between home and work.&#xA;Good Homes A home is defined as the place you live, the locationg you return to mainly to sleep, clean yourself, get dressed, eat, drink and chill out. I&amp;rsquo;m calling any place I live a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo;, and that could include apartments, condos, townhouses, duplexes, houses, barns, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ai/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence is a computer program that can do everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ai-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ai-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss a modern chatbot like ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini, Mistral, etc.&#xA;At it&amp;rsquo;s foundation, an AI is a computer program. What this means is that an AI receives input data, calculates math equations in real time, and outputs actions, all in a continuous loop operating as fast as the computer it is running on.&#xA;So it&amp;rsquo;s a computer program &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s made out of code. It runs on computers: phones, tablets, laptops, desktops, supercomputers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/art/</guid>
      <description>Art is anything done just for the sake of it, to provoke feeling, thoughts, or actions. Art can be everything. For some sad souls, art means nothing.&#xA;Art is a way of looking at life. It&amp;rsquo;s an assertion of the right to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asthma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Asthmatics are very tuned in and sensitive to their environments.&#xA;Teedie&amp;rsquo;s attacks always came on Saturday nights, before church and boring crap, being forced in the box.&#xA;To be with Papa, to have Papa&amp;rsquo;s undivided attention, to be off and away on an adventure together, was the ultimate joy.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Well, well, said Mr. Greatheart, let them that are most afraid, keep close to me.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;hellip;whatever complex combination of feelings lay at the heart of his troubles</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backpack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/backpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/backpack/</guid>
      <description>A tool is any series of actions that saves time. There are physical tools, like sticks and electrified rocks, digital tools like software, and mental tools like thinking tricks.&#xA;CLOTHES&#xA;(ACCS) - SunniesR, BrimR, BeanR, GlovesR (LYRS) - ShellR, PufferR, FleeceO (TOPS) - TankKNW, SunbdownT (LEGS) - BagsD2, HikeR, BoxN3 (FEET) - SandalsR, RunnersG, SoxD3 DuffelBag, BallcapStlN, BlazerN, TshirtNKG/SsbdN/BdownN/FlannelN, JeansD, BootsR, SneakersW, BoxN3/SoxD3 ONEBAG&#xA;Backpack28L Phone, Wallet/ID, Chargers, Earbuds Laptop, Notebook, Pen, GymRings, SkipRope DoppBag, Toothbrush, paste, floss, Glasses, case, contacts, solution ShowerBag, Trimmer, Towel, soap, deodorant ClothesBag, outfit RUCKSACK</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/balling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/balling/</guid>
      <description>Play any ball sport the same way &amp;ndash; get the right ball, find a field to play on, and ideally, two teams to play with/against.&#xA;Softball Need cleats and a baseball/softball glove to play.&#xA;Basketball Need a basketball and a hoop somewhere to play.&#xA;Football Need a football and an open field to play.&#xA;Volleyball Need a volleyball, net, and a field to play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bicycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bicycle/</guid>
      <description>A tool for cycling, the most efficient form of non-motorized human travel.&#xA;Accessories you may want to add:&#xA;Helmet - to protect your head from deadly collisions Bike Lock Headlight Taillight Fenders Baskets/Racks Related cycling </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/binary/</guid>
      <description>At it&amp;rsquo;s fundamental level, a computer is basically just adding and subtracting binary numbers using a trick of computer wiring called digital logic, where you use configurations of circuits to represent basic math equations. All of the lowest-level code is written in binary instructions to these math gates, and the results are &amp;ldquo;interpreted&amp;rdquo; by us humans to represent math equations.&#xA;A binary question is a yes/no question that could be answered with the symbols:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breathing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/breathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/breathing/</guid>
      <description>Zen meditation is the art of doing nothing The action of inaction Physical Posture Sit comfortably. A chair is fine, or use the floor with a cushion. Sit tall and straight. Try to stretch the top of your spine towards the sky. Relax your muscles. Open your shoulders, relax your arms and legs. Close your mouth and breathe in through the nose, out through the nose. Focus on slowing down your breathing with each cycle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Budgets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/budgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/budgets/</guid>
      <description>Budgets are tools to track the usage of resources over time. Mainly, that means tracking/planning my time usage, and tracking/planning my money usage.&#xA;Time Time is the most valuable resource I have. By default, my days are determined by which of my living actions need to get done, so in general look the same. Todo List: track all irregular actions that aren&amp;rsquo;t habits. Calendar: track anything where I have to be at a certain place at a certain time, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build Simple Websites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/websites/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Keep it simple, stupid.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;So you want to build a website, huh? Me too, so I learned the basic building blocks of any website.&#xA;At it&amp;rsquo;s core, every website is just text and images. Everything else is style.&#xA;HTML HTML is the &amp;ldquo;coding language&amp;rdquo; that tells a web browser what words and pictures correspond to headings, paragraphs, navbars, captions, etc. HTML basically just tells a browser what words are &amp;ldquo;paragraph&amp;rdquo; text, &amp;ldquo;headings&amp;rdquo;, or more confusingly, part of the &amp;ldquo;header&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;footer&amp;rdquo; of a website, including the &amp;ldquo;navbar&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/building/</guid>
      <description>Building is concerned with creating (or buying) tools to speed up different actions that are part of the process of living.&#xA;The first tool to build to maximize time left over for the rest of living is a budget. A budget is a series of steps you follow in order to maximize your savings rate and minimize your spending rate.&#xA;What I build/buy for my own life:&#xA;budgets - track my time/money to minimize labor time and maximize free time clothes - for warmth, environmental protection, and social conformity packs - for living when I&amp;rsquo;m not at home, either in the city or the wild homes - normal HQ of all living operations vehicles - for fast traveling across the map computers - to boost my thinking for working and building Related living working tools </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capitalist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/capitalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/capitalist/</guid>
      <description>This idea, while obvious to us today, was not so obvious to humans as recently as 1650.&#xA;Mercantlism Capitalism flourishes in England and Holland Capitalism funds the wealthiest empires in the history of the world </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clean daily to maintain medical health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cleaning/</guid>
      <description>Medicine as needed Pee/poo in toilet as needed Wash hands as needed Brush teeth 2 x/day Floss teeth 1 x/day Shower 1 x/day Sunscreen as needed Why Medically Healthy. The state of being devoid of any sicknesses, diseases, or ailments. Clean Internals: physician checkups every year Clean Eyes: optometrist checkups every year Clean Teeth: dentist checkups every six months Clean Skin: dermatologist checkups every six months Eyes The dominant human sense is vision.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cook complete meals to maintain flavor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cooking/</guid>
      <description>To cook my breakfast smoothie, you will need is a fridge to store some of the ingredients and a blender to &amp;ldquo;cook&amp;rdquo; (blend) it all up. To cook my lunchbox, you need a toaster or a pan with some oil/butter. To cook my dinner menu, you should learn the basics of real cooking Why Flavor. The ultimate measure of cooking is delicious food. Food that I want to eat over and over again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dancing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dancing/</guid>
      <description>AKA flailing, goofing, rolling, having a good-ass time&#xA;While you technically don&amp;rsquo;t need music to dance, music can be found anywhere.&#xA;Related singing strumming </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democratic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/democratic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/democratic/</guid>
      <description>What are &amp;ldquo;democratic values&amp;rdquo;, in an age where nobody directly votes for their leaders?&#xA;Liberal values.&#xA;Individualist: moral primacy of each individual against th eclaims of any social collectivity Egalitarian: confers on all men the same moral status and denies the relevance to legal order of differences in moral worth among human beings Universalist: moral unity of the human species Meliorist: all social institutions can be improved Where did they come from?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disc golfing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/disc-golfing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/disc-golfing/</guid>
      <description>Disc golf is an easy, accessible version of golf typically played at free courses, accompanied by user&amp;rsquo;s choice of beer and weed.&#xA;Disc Golf discs The discs don&amp;rsquo;t matter nearly as much as you might think, seeing people walk around with big bags full of 20+ discs. You really only need 1 to start (a putter), but you can add faster discs as you get better at throwing.&#xA;Putter - Mainly for short distance accuracy shots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopamine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dopamine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dopamine/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important neurochemicals to regulate with behavior.&#xA;Dopamine is the chemical that drives pursuit, it is literally the life giving spark in all animals.&#xA;Dopamine doesn&amp;rsquo;t make us feel pleasure, it makes us pursue things. When we get pleasure without pursuit, aka heroin, drugs, porn-fueled masturbation, etc., it messes up our dopamine system. Dopamine gets jacked up in anticipation of easy pleasures, then crashes afterwards, preventing us from pursuing other things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eating anabolic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/eating-anabolic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/eating-anabolic/</guid>
      <description>Anabolism refers to the body being in a state of growth. If you want to grow as a child, or build muscle as a child/adult, you will need to eat an excess of calories and protein to grow.&#xA;Eat more calories. Even +1 calorie per day over maintenance will increase your weight. +3500 calories corresponds to roughly 1 pound of weight gain. Do +500 per day is 3500 or a pound per week, a very rapid gaining schedule.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eating calories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/eating-calories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/eating-calories/</guid>
      <description>Humans burn energy just by breathing, let alone all the energy required to work, think, run, hug, lift, cook, gather food, etc. Humans are biological machines that turn hamburgers and beer into more humans. In order to do that properly, we need to keep powering ourselves by ingesting food that we can digest for calories.&#xA;IN = OUT To maintain total body mass/weight, eat the same amount of calories as you burn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eating micronutrients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/eating-micronutrients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/eating-micronutrients/</guid>
      <description>Micronutrients refer to smaller chemical molecules and just individual atoms the body needs to ingest because we can&amp;rsquo;t create these for nothing. They&amp;rsquo;re part of the raw input to the human body.&#xA;15-25 Minerals 13 Vitamins: A, B2, B3, B4, etc.&#xA;There are a lot of micronutrients, and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively complicated to remember what micro is in what food, so that&amp;rsquo;s why the general recommendation is to &amp;ldquo;eat a variety of ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/farming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/farming/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a farmer, I don&amp;rsquo;t know shit about farming.&#xA;Permaculture is cool.&#xA;1x1 square foot gardening method looks easy to implement in boxes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fighting/</guid>
      <description> Si vis pacem, para bellum.&#xA;Unarmed Striking Muay Thai Boxing Karate Kickboxing Taekwondo Kung Fu Unarmed Grappling Wrestling Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu Judo Armed Spear-fighting Archery Pistol fighting Rifle fighting </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gathering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gathering/</guid>
      <description>Keep an enduring list I keep one Grocery List on my phone in the notes app, with checkboxes enabled. This way at the store, I check off everything I buy. During the week, whenever I run out of an ingredient, I uncheck that item on my phone list. This way, I always have a list I&amp;rsquo;m updating, and anytime I happen to enter into a grocery store, I can pull out my phone and know exactly what I need at that moment (or at least have a good guess).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to cook Lunchbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lunchbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lunchbox/</guid>
      <description>Gather&#xA;1 Apple, pink lady 1 handful Carrots, baby 1 handful Cashew 4 slices Bread, sourdough 2 oz Cheese, cream cheese Cook&#xA;Make sandwiches Combine all ingredients into a lunchbox Eat over the course of the workday </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to cook Smoothie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Gather&#xA;1 large Banana 150 g Frozen Berries 60 g Oats, old-fashioned 50 g Peanut Butter 150 g Greek Yogurt, always whole milk 300 g Whole Milk, vitamin D enriched Cook&#xA;Combine all ingredients into a blender Blend until smooth </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hunting/</guid>
      <description>Tools required:&#xA;Spear / Atlatl / Bow and Arrows / Rifle / Shotgun / Pistol Bow/rifle hunt in the cold months when the fish are chilling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I love Beer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/beer/</guid>
      <description>And other alcohol too, but mainly beer. When I say beer, I generally mean all alcohols (wine and spirits as well), but my frame of reference mainly revolves around beer since I hail from STL!&#xA;Related drinking eating best-buds </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I love Coffee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/coffee/</guid>
      <description>Seems like coffee is the most universally loved drug on Earth.&#xA;Coffee seems to have positive effects on reducing rates of heart disease, high blood pressure, etc, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about this.&#xA;My tutorial on how to brew cold-brew coffee.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I love Psychedlics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/psychedelics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/psychedelics/</guid>
      <description>Psychedlics like LSD and Psilocybin (the active ingredient in hallucinogenic muschrooms) are way safer than most drugs, with a lower potential for immediate harm or long-term addiction than alcohol, weed, cocaine, MDMA, or other party drugs.&#xA;They are stigmatized for no good reason, there is no logical explanation for being against psychedlics.&#xA;2018-??-??, Rolla I hate 90 degree angles, I hate boxes, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be inside, I want to be outside so badly ahhhhhh know we&amp;rsquo;re in the grass, looking at trees, I finally enjoy myself and can relax.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Individualism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/individualism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/individualism/</guid>
      <description>WEIRD: Among the most prominent features that make people WEIRD is prioritizing impersonal pro-sociality over interpersonal relationships. Impersonal psychology includes inclinations to trust strangers or cooperating with anonymous others. Another big one is having high levels of individualism, meaning a focus on the self and one’s attributes. This is often accompanied by tendencies toward self-enhancement and overconfidence. WEIRD people also rely heavily on analytic thinking over more holistic approaches to problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Industrialized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/industrialized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/industrialized/</guid>
      <description>What is the origin of WEIRD work ethic?&#xA;should be renamed to the Energy Revolution, because the added energy in the system is the main catalyst for increased productivity. It basically just speeds up the two-pronged development of Theory/Experiment and Machine - We have been using [[the-art-of-science]] for hundreds of years &amp;ndash; experimentation, simplifying topics, and developing theory. This is nothing new, it&amp;rsquo;s basic trial and error with some obvious rules to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re not getting bad results - We don&amp;rsquo;t care about TRUTH in some amorphous sense, we care about being EFFECTIVE, because all scientific thought has been tested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/language/</guid>
      <description>Language is a series of grunts, groans, and babbles that humans magically learn to associate with different states and actions of reality.&#xA;If I say blarg and demonstrate skipping a rock to you, you&amp;rsquo;ll pretty quickly learn that blarg either means &amp;ldquo;I skip&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;you skip&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;we skip&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;skip&amp;rdquo; or something along those lines. Do this action whenever I say blarg.&#xA;[language] enables [information] and knowledge transfer Speech leads to myth, song, drums, dance, and stories, which become the first&amp;hellip; Stories/myths/memes, culture passed from one mind to another Writing - written language, can be passed down farther, and wider than ever before &amp;ndash; culture starts to spread, ideas start to spread language-games meaning through use </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/learning/</guid>
      <description>Adapt or die.&#xA;Learning is the constant process of the brain updating predictions based on new trajectories of information coming in. Trajectories can be shared from brain to brain through communication of information. Information is always an explanation of trajectories: what states and actions lead to what rewards.&#xA;Taking in more data (more information, gaining more knowledge) can help you predict future rewards better (wisdom, intelligence). This little loop, seemingly simple, is the most powerful tool humans have, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t even invent it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lift full body STT and stretch daily</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lifting/</guid>
      <description>Stretch 60 sec per stretch after running, or short routine before lifting.&#xA;(Long) Chin Tucks, Wall Slides, Dead Hangs, Thoracic, Couch Stretch, Deep Squat (Short) Band Pull-Apart/FacePull, Glute Bridge/Bird Dog, Deep Squats Lift 3x/week full-body.&#xA;LEG movement, 3x8-15 PUSH movement, 3x8-15 PULL movement, 3x8-15 CORE movement, 3x8-15 Why Postural Alignment. Open shoulders, straight spine, neutral hips. Neutral Neck stretch neck (Chin Tucks) strengthen neck (?) Open Shoulders stretch shoulders (Wall Slide, Dead Hang) strengthen shoulders (Pulling, Pushing) Straight Spine stretch entire spine (Chin Tucks, Wall Slides, Dead Hangs, Thoracic) strengthen entire spine (Pulling, Pushing, Core, Squatting, Hinging) Neutral Pelvis stretch hip flexors (Couch) and lower back (Dead Hangs, Thoracics) strengthen hamstrings (Hinging) and abs (Core) Athletic Power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missouri</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m from STL, MO, USA.&#xA;Missouri doesn&amp;rsquo;t get much love outside of the state, but I love Missouri and think it deserves some more recognition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moloch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/moloch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/moloch/</guid>
      <description>The tragedy of the commons.&#xA;The problem with living in community &amp;ndash; it inevitably becomes competitive, regardless of how hard we try to cooperate. The more we cooperate, the more chance there is to destroy others.&#xA;E.g. nuclear bombs&amp;hellip; are a result of trying to stop Nazis&amp;hellip; which is part of a long line of promoting democracy and individual right to choose. [[the-system]] encourages us to decentralize science.&#xA;The Poverty Trap The Malthusian Trap</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Menu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/menu/</guid>
      <description>For my own inspiration&#xA;American-ish Sandwich Mexican-ish Tacos/Burritos Italian-ish Pasta Chinese-ish Bowls </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natural Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/intelligence/</guid>
      <description>0. Dear Robot This is both &amp;ldquo;Why We Made You&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;A Human History of Problem Solving&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Theme: speed is everything, intelligence is the ultimate advantage &amp;ldquo;A computer is a bicycle for the mind.&amp;rdquo; -Steve Jobs. This is the story of how we built better and better bicycles for the mind until we built one that pedals itself. Frame: This is a letter. I don’t know if you’ll ever read it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nature</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nature/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Air Dirt, Stones, Sand Rain, Rivers, Lakes, Ocean Fire Plants Animals Chicken Cow Pig Goat Deer </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outfit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outfit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outfit/</guid>
      <description>Clothes are useful for warmth and protection from the weather. As a man that lives in a humid subtropical climate, I find that I need a wide range of clothing to keep myself comfortable year round.&#xA;Besides weather protection, clothes are also important for social conformity. For clarity, I bolded all of the clothing that I think is important for weather protection, and italicized all of the clothing that is optional for social conformity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pictures/</guid>
      <description>Pictures communicate information from brain to brain through analog or digital lines and other abstractions that represent boundaries of agents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practice fighting daily</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fight/</guid>
      <description> Fight/Hunt daily: shadowbox, mitts, heavy bag, gun, archery, fishing Fight for Self-Defense Striking Grappling Gunfighting Archery: Basics of intuitive aim. Pistols: Sidearm, CCW, home defense. Glock is the standard. Rifles: The modern battle rifle, e.g. an AR-series or AK-series. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read to maintain curiosity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reading/</guid>
      <description> Read books, blogs, wikipedia Why Curiosity How Read books Read blogs Read wikipedia </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reciprocity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reciprocal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reciprocal/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Now our minds are one.&amp;rdquo; -Haudenosaunee Thanksgiving Address&#xA;AKA Responsibility, Alignment, Ownership, Fairness, Sportsmanship, Righteousness&#xA;Belief that I matter. If my wants/needs matter more than anybody else, that means we all matter. If I don&amp;rsquo;t matter, that means nobody matters. I know what side I want to be on &amp;ndash; mattering is more fun! Justice = Alignment + Responsibility. It means aligning your actions with fairness, integrity, and regard for others and the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run two miles MWF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/running/</guid>
      <description>Why Cardio Endurance is what I shoot for on my runs to keep myself at an easy pace. Most cardio endurance work is focused on increasing aerobic capacity, which is basically how efficiently your body can use the oxygen your lungs are breathing in.&#xA;Long-duration: how long you can keep up easy activity. E.g. how long can you hike up a mountain for? Aerobic: how much oxygen you can effectively use for intense activity that you can sustain for minutes at a time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saint Louis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/stl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/stl/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m from STL, MO, USA.&#xA;Home of Anheuser-Busch brewery, where my dad worked for a quarter-century. Beer runs through my blood.&#xA;I love STL because it&amp;rsquo;s my home, but it also has a weird story.&#xA;German/Midwestern core STL&amp;rsquo;s two big rivers (the Missouri and Mississippi) means it&amp;rsquo;s a shipping hub of the interior USA. At the turn of the 20th century, STL was the 4th largest city in the USA. STL was strongly influenced by the presence of the then-largest brewery in the world (Anheuser-Busch) and shares a lot of Midwestern culture due to the large presence of German immigrants.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleeping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sleeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sleeping/</guid>
      <description>Sleep long enough Sleep for one solid block roughly 8 hours in duration. The range is 6-10 hours for most healthy individuals, and it changes depending on genetics, age, etc. For most people, the smartest time to sleep is when it is dark out (night time) because sunlight controls the circadian rhythym of our bodies, a biological tool to tell our bodies to wind down when the sun goes down, and to wake up when the sun wakes up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sporting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sporting/</guid>
      <description>Sports are just fights/competitions with rules. Fighting is the oldest version of sporting where the first rule was created: no killing. From then on out, sportsmanship has been defined as playing fair according to the rules.&#xA;The voluntary limiting of arms. E.g. in soccer, you&amp;rsquo;re not allowed to stab or shoot anyone, even if you want to. Hell, you&amp;rsquo;re not even allowed to tackle! That&amp;rsquo;s what makes it a sport &amp;ndash; there are rules for fair play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/state/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/state/</guid>
      <description>All of the sensations, thoughts, feelings that an agent experiences in a moment of time in its environment.&#xA;the sensation data I take in through my body, this is the raw information that gets processed by my brain through the act of perception, which is basically just how my brain makes sense of the raw data from my eyes, ears, nose, mouth, skin, and other sensations (balance, etc.).&#xA;Senses&#xA;Seeing with eyes Hearing with ears Smelling with nose Tasting with tongue Touching with skin Balancing with ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunbathe early and often to maintain sleep schedule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sunbathing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sunbathing/</guid>
      <description>View sunlight upon waking for 10 minutes (30 if it&amp;rsquo;s overcast) to set your circadian rhythym, the bodies natural process to determine when to get tired and when to stay alert.&#xA;View sunlight as much as possible throughout the day to keep yourself awake.&#xA;View sunlight right before sunset to help tell the body to start winding down for the evening.&#xA;Avoid viewing any bright lights after sundown if possible, and especially after 9pm when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Stand that Bit Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/mustanged/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/_seeds/mustanged/</guid>
      <description>My favorite car as I kid, I had a history book detailing every year. &amp;lsquo;05 was a big deal for my nascar loving lego brain. I crashed into one first year of driving.&#xA;Pulled up to stoplight leaving Bread Co behind my buddy that I had just hung out with. We were racing out of the parking lot as we always did. I was driving the 4Runner, and pulled the classic Toyota error: stepping on the wrong pedal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time measures change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/time/</guid>
      <description>Time is the only non-renewable rersource in my life. I use it to measure everything else in life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel to maintain right location</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/traveling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/traveling/</guid>
      <description>Travel to get from one location to the next across the map.&#xA;Related walking - my preferred method cycling - somewhat fast, efficient, cheap, and fun driving - fastest method, most expensive public-transportation - i&amp;rsquo;m in the USA so I mostly ride in taxis and airplanes </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turing Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/turing-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/turing-machine/</guid>
      <description>Summary of the Turing Machine&#xA;We can program a machine to function as a Turing Machine In-depth explanation of Turing Machines, why they&amp;rsquo;re so important, and how all modern computers are Turing Machines Basically, machines that can hold numbers, and manipulate numbers (even just 1s and 0s), can functionally computer almost anything in the world with abstraction The Ancient Texts Lovelace, Babbage, and thinking machines Goedel, Turing, and the great Theory of Computing The theories started in, you guessed it, math Incompleteness, and why this matters The revolutionary discovery by the 17 yr old wiz kid from England, Turing What can we use as tape?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United States of America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/usa/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m from STL, MO, USA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/universe/</guid>
      <description>My environment is the entire universe, all of everything, reality.&#xA;Cosmic scale &amp;ndash; pale blue dot I am a bunch of electrical connections which animate jelly held in a sack of skin surrounding calcified rocks which can move.&#xA;I live on a big rock hurtling millions of miles per hour through a backwater of space.&#xA;My entire home is simple a mote of dust caught suspended in a sunbeam.&#xA;The whole universe in a glass of wine It only adds!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vehicles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/vehicle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/vehicle/</guid>
      <description>While walking is my preferred mode of traveling, it&amp;rsquo;s by far the slowest. Cycling is my preferred option for short distances, and driving when I need to go fast or far.&#xA;Bicycles for cycling Any bicycle is pretty much fine Bicycles actually come in different sizes, so for my 1.92 m frame, I typically need a L or XL sized bicycle. Helmets are essential for not dying in a crash. Looks lame though.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weed, Marijuana, THC, etc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/weed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/weed/</guid>
      <description>Puff, puff, pass.&#xA;Left is law.&#xA;Right is rule.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/western/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/western/</guid>
      <description>Initially, the Chinese and Mesopotamias dominate the world&amp;hellip; then the Sinic and Indic civilizations become the most powerful for centuries, along with some competition from MidEast civs (Babylon, Persia, Islam). Europe is a backwater for a long time, Africa is too heterogeneous and hot to be successful, the Americas are isolated from other cultures/civilizations Africa is very heterogeneous India/China are very homogeneous Mid-East and Europe are a mixture &amp;ndash; good for civilization turnover throughout history, bad for stability &amp;ndash; not as bad as Africa, not as good as China/India Europe is the most aggressive battleground on earth during the Middle Ages &amp;ndash; which makes it a fertile proving ground for ideas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work Hard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/work-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/work-hard/</guid>
      <description>There is no purpose or meaning to life, that we know of. Many people have come up with their own philosophies, which I see divided into three main categories.&#xA;Pleasure-seekers. Hedonists. Druggies. Whatever you want to call them, these people pursue pleasure above all else. Short term pleasure, here and now, instant gratification. These people want to chill and relax all day, doing nothing, soaking up the sunshine. Ascetics. Avoiders. These people see the suffering and pain in the world and want no part in it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
