<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Blake Ruprecht</title>
    <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Blake Ruprecht</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to use Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/reinforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/reinforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>RL is a learning paradigm Reinforcement Learning (RL) is a machine learning paradigm. By that I mean it&amp;rsquo;s the way we tell the computer ML agent if it won or lost. Or if it&amp;rsquo;s right or wrong.
You know how agents are run on computers, right? The computers are calculating a bunch of equations. These equations determine the totality of what the agent perceives in the real world, as well as the decision-making process to choose actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delicious Creamy Brah Sauce recipe</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/dcbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/dcbs/</guid>
      <description>INGREDIENTS
Fresh
1/2 cup Cashews soaked 25 Habaneros roughly chopped 1 Yellow Bell Pepper roughly chopped 10 Garlic Cloves smashed 1 Onion roughly chopped 1/2 Lemon juiced Pantry
1 quart White Vinegar 2 Tbsp Apple Cider Vinegar 2 Tbsp Maple Syrup 2 Tbsp Soy Sauce 2 Tbsp Olive Oil 1 Tbsp Sesame Oil 4 tsp Mustard Powder 1 tsp Turmeric Powder INSTRUCTIONS
Soak Cashews in water for 30 min Prep Habaneros, Yellow Bell Pepper, Garlic, Onion Saute Olive Oil, Onion, Garlic until softened Add Habaneros, Yellow Bell Pepper Add White Vinegar, Apple Cider Vinegar, Maple Syrup, Soy Sauce, Sesame Oil, Mustard Powder, Turmeric Powder Bring to a boil, then reduce to a simmer, simmer for 30-45 min (longer is less spicy) Taste and adjust for seasoning Blend in a food processor/blender Pour into sauce jars About Originally invented by James S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditation teaches the Way</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/meditation/</guid>
      <description>Meditation is the art of inaction. It&amp;rsquo;s the practice of doing nothing. While there are numerous benefits of meditation for overall health and well-being, and often neglected benefit of meditation is how it helps you do everything else. Since you learn to quiet your thoughts about the past and future and focus totally on the present, meditation develops the quality of mind that is necessary for success in almost every other endeavor &amp;ndash; attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfectionism is tough to recognize</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/perfectionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/perfectionism/</guid>
      <description>What is it?
Procrastination Fear of failure leads to procrastination Creates a vicious cycle All-or-nothing thinking Strive for perfect or flawless, almost perfect is seen as a failure Focused only on results High achievers can enjoy the process of chasing a goal as much or more than the actual reaching of the goal itself. Conversely, perfectionists see the goal and nothing else. They’re so concerned with hitting the goal and avoiding failure that they can’t enjoy the process of growing and striving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My quest for the perfect bowl of Noodle Soup</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/noodle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/noodle-soup/</guid>
      <description>Holy shit, it&amp;rsquo;s all coming together. After watching Kung Fu Panda as a kid, I&amp;rsquo;ve been craving a delicious Asian nooodle-soup dish. Instant ramen is a good solution for $1 and a heart attack, but I want something fresh, wholesome, and delicious. Before this journey, ramen never did it for me, and other dishes like Pad Thai and Lo Mein just didn&amp;rsquo;t hit the spot.
I never liked Thai food, and I&amp;rsquo;m a serious food explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do it yourself EV charger installation</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/install-an-ev-charger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/install-an-ev-charger/</guid>
      <description>For the record, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend you install an EV charger yourself if you have no electrical experience. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely dangerous, and if you mess up, you can very easily catch your house on fire, or worse. However, it&amp;rsquo;s cool to at least now the process in theory, and this way, you can see if your electrician is doing it properly as well.
How much does it cost? If it was free, everyone would do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insects are a great source of nutrients</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/insect-farming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/insect-farming/</guid>
      <description>I ate a scorpion in Bangkok and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t good. The outer shell dominated the texture, and the meat tasted vaguely stale. Would not recommend.
I also ate grasshoppers, crickets, mealworms, and bamboo worms. I liked them all, and liked the mealworms so much I bought them many more times for a crunchy snack. They reminded me of a meatier cheese puff &amp;ndash; salty, crunchy, and airy. The crickets had much more substance to them, but were suprisingly good, with a roasted, fishy flavor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Python</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/how-to-install-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/how-to-install-python/</guid>
      <description>I entered the software field as a mechanical engineer. Even with technical experience and some coding experience, I found the entire software world quite daunting. All of the documentation I read assumed I already knew stuff like what this ~ symbol meant, or how to input something like $ cd home into my computer. Where is the money application on my computer?
If you&amp;rsquo;re as fresh and new as I was, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably appreciate a step-by-step guide to figuring all of this out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do work you enjoy</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/work/</guid>
      <description>There is no purpose or meaning to life, that we know of. Many people have come up with their own philosophies, which I see divided into three main categories.
Pleasure-seekers. Hedonists. Druggies. Whatever you want to call them, these people pursue pleasure above all else. Short term pleasure, here and now, instant gratification. These people want to chill and relax all day, doing nothing, soaking up the sunshine. Ascetics. Avoiders. These people see the suffering and pain in the world and want no part in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A collection of thoughts on Solarpunk</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/solarpunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/solarpunk/</guid>
      <description>Basically Deep ecology, Anarcho communism, but seemingly more hopeful.
Solarpunk Current knowledge of human happiness Deep ecology, sustainability taken farther Engineering green energy, composite wood buildings, green architecture, water? Permaculture Bicycling, Public transportation Walkable cities Peace The &amp;ldquo;Hierarchy&amp;rdquo; of Needs is really a circle Peace and Love, I&amp;rsquo;m a dirty hippie Clocks are a capitalist invention to keep the common man down The rhythms of the natural world are forgotten We are not robots, we are large mammals who want to finish up work by noon to go surf and dance Wage-slavery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple software follows Unix principles</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/simple-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/simple-software/</guid>
      <description>Software is hard I just want to say that I find software quite difficult to work with, and I in theory have a masters degree in computer science. My argument against that is my degree focuses on math, not programming, so anything to do with turning on a computer and getting it to work makes me feel like a monkey. Eventually, I learned that software is a lot like building Lego sets &amp;ndash; the instructions tell you everything you need to know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My memories are stored in melodies</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/my-memories-in-melodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/my-memories-in-melodies/</guid>
      <description>The greatest distance between two places is through time. When I listen to music, occasionally a song will play that instantly transports me back to a specific moment in time, filling me with vivid memories of a moment I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget. When I play through these songs, I relive moments like they just happened.
Somewhere in the Middle One moment, it&amp;rsquo;s a hot and humid day somewhere in the middle of a damp Missouri summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitting naked in a snowy field</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/sitting-naked/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/sitting-naked/</guid>
      <description>The Basics I want to enjoy life as much as possible. I can guarantee that you do too. Everyone I know pretty much wants the same things out of life &amp;ndash; friendships, good food, plenty of sleep, a healthy body, a calm mind. Tons of money? Only insofar as it buys you food, a place to live, plenty of warm clothes, and some beers to share with our friends. Most of the time, we seek things outside of the basics because of what we lack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something I should say more</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/i-love-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/i-love-you/</guid>
      <description>The tattoo on my achilles heel is an X. If you squint, it kind of looks like an intersection, or a crossroad. To me, this represents indecision, my biggest weakness, and the thing I regret most in life &amp;ndash; not taking action to pursue love over fear. As I sit here at another crossroad, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think of the lyrics from the song that inspired the ink:
I&amp;rsquo;m standing at the crossroad,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packing light for world travel is easy</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/packing-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/packing-light/</guid>
      <description>Since I became an adult, I&amp;rsquo;ve always set out to travel with just one backpack so I never have to wait at that stupid baggage carousel thing. It&amp;rsquo;s never been a problem.
I recently completed a four month trip around Southeast Asia and Europe lasting from February through June. Prior to this, I traveled around the USA pretty extensively for some months. I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled a lot over the past few years, but this was by far the most travel I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done in a one-year period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set grocery shopping PRs</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/grocery-shopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/grocery-shopping/</guid>
      <description>I went grocery shopping with my buddy recently and was totally baffled when we did the unthinkable: we backtracked. We went back to the produce section not once, but twice, making three total trips through the same section. Grocery shopping is my least favorite part of the eating experience, yet it seems to be a necessity for most people. My garden is non-existent, and my foraging skills are abysmal, so the next best option is to take my hard-earned cash into the big unwindowed box of fluorescent lighting and try to navigate the dense forest of packaged items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Theory applies math to behavior</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/game-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/game-theory/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Intelligence is the ability to get what you want.&amp;rdquo;
As agents, we set goals and figure out how to achieve them. That&amp;rsquo;s what being smart is. Being intelligent is not the ability to learn 100 digits of Pi. That&amp;rsquo;s just pure computation. Being intelligent is reciting those digits to a girl you have a crush on, but only if it works. If she gets the ick, then that behavior was dumb, unless you were purely competing with yourself, in which case it&amp;rsquo;s back to being smart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>SUMMARY: Change your mindset to prioritize growth by praising yourself for effort, hard-work, and learning. Talk to yourself like a friend, don&amp;rsquo;t try to be perfect, and engage in positive self-talk. Eventually, you will be making more progress than you ever were with a fixed mindset.
1. What is growth mindset A growth mindset is when you believe you can improve at anything with time and effort. Instead of seeing challenges as an internal problem, you see them as a chance to get better and improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy cold brew method</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/brew-coffee-cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/brew-coffee-cold/</guid>
      <description>Summary of this essay Why brew yourself? How to brew well Water: 40% of the flavor Fresh beans: 40% of the flavor Freshly ground: 10% of the flavor Brewing consistency: 10% of the flavor The process References Why brew yourself? I go to coffee shops and do not understand how cold brew coffee costs significantly more than hot brew. It must be down to marketing, and the fact that people who don&amp;rsquo;t give a hoot typically aren&amp;rsquo;t going to coffee shops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSTM units incorporate temporal data into NNs</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/long-short-term-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/long-short-term-memory/</guid>
      <description>Utilizes temporal data, aka LSTM units can use previous information in their determination of current state.
![[transformer diagram.png]]
The first sigmoid is the &amp;ldquo;forget-gate&amp;rdquo; $f_t$, the second sigmoid is the &amp;ldquo;input-gate&amp;rdquo;, $i_t$, the tanh is the &amp;ldquo;cell-update&amp;rdquo;, $\tilde{C}_t$. Forget-gate will determine how much of the previous cell-state we need to remember, input-gate determines how much of the new cell-state we need to remember, and cell-update gate normalizes the cell-state between [-1,1] because of the tanh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIs learn through a variety of learning paradigms.</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/machine-learning-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/machine-learning-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>date +++
Supervised Data comes with labels. The network learns the labels associated with the data. It works pretty well, given the labels actually fit the data, otherwise you get lots of False Positives and False Negatives, semantically.
Unsupervised Different techniques are used to learn structure from data. Problem, is there any true underlying structure to data? Do clusters actually exist? It&amp;rsquo;s useful to cluster often, but hard to prove validity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANFIS has gradient problems</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/anfis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/anfis/</guid>
      <description>A Fuzzy Neural Network The first major project I worked on was coding up the Adaptive Neuro Fuzzy Inference System (ANFIS) in Python, specifically utilizing the PyTorch package to calculate the gradients. I calculated the gradients by hand to validate PyTorch, but wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you know it, PyTorch knows what it&amp;rsquo;s doing.
ANFIS is a type of artificial neural network that combines the antecedent and consequent logic (fuzzy IF-THEN rules) of fuzzy logic with the backpropagation learning techniques of multilayer perceptrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action or entropy</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/action-or-entropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/action-or-entropy/</guid>
      <description>A meditation to myself.
Responsibility is literally my &amp;ldquo;response ability&amp;rdquo;. I cannot choose my circumstances, or what the people around me are doing. All I can choose is how I respond. Previously I called this &amp;ldquo;hell yes or no&amp;rdquo;, but that can be a little confusing. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you have to love every decision you make, or be in love with what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. It just means that taking action is a choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reward drives behavior</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/reward-drives-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/reward-drives-behavior/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s all about sex. Or money. Or good food.
Reward.
If you want to win a game, you should reward yourself only for winning. Not for time spent practicing, not for time spent reading, not for anything else besides winning. Don&amp;rsquo;t reward yourself for &amp;ldquo;playing hard&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;trying&amp;rdquo;, or for &amp;ldquo;having fun&amp;rdquo;, or doing one aspect of the game well. Sure, these tricks may be helpful to keep you playing, but they don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily help you win.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural gas learns a self-organizing map</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/neural-gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/neural-gas/</guid>
      <description>Similar to [[Kohonen map]], a Self-organing Map, but the topology is learned. Goal is to learn a topological structure to relate &amp;ldquo;close&amp;rdquo; datapoints to each other. Winner-takes-most. Growing neural gas starts with two-neurons and keeps adding a bisecting neuron until the stopping criteria is met (e.g. performance measure below threshold)
Algorithm Given an input dataset $x \in \mathbb{R}^n$ Init &amp;ldquo;weights&amp;rdquo; $w_i \in \mathbb{R}^n$ Pick a datapoint $v$ from $x$, For each weight $w_i$, calculate the distance to $v$ For each weight, determine the number (cardinality?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithm to beat procrastination</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/algorithm-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/algorithm-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>$$ Motivation = \frac{Expectancy \cdot Value}{Impulsiveness \cdot Delay} $$
Step 1: Notice I&amp;rsquo;m procrastinating I know I should do a task Step 2: Guess which unattacked part of the equation is causing me the most trouble. Low Expectancy: am I likely to succeed? Is the task within my capabilities? Will I actually get the reward? Low Value: am I bored and distracted? Uncomfortable, onerous, or painful? Am I nervous or afraid of the outcome?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Choquet Integral generalizes many metric functions.</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/choquet-integral/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/choquet-integral/</guid>
      <description>Where $\pi(j)$ sorts the inputs based on their output values, $h_{\pi(j)}$, which is the output for input $x_j$. Little g is a measure such that $g(A) &amp;lt; g(B)$ if $A \subseteq B$, $g(\emptyset) = 0$, $g(\mathbf{X}) = 1$. ChI adheres to monotonicity, idempotency, subcontinuity, etc. This includes the Linear Order Statistic (LOS) the Order Weighted Average (OWA), Maximum, Minimum, etc. $$ \int h \odot g = C_g(h) = \sum_{j=1}^N h_{\pi(i)} \left( g(A_{\pi(j)}) - g(A_{\pi(j-1)}) \right) $$ $\pi$ is the function that sorts the inputs according to their values $h(x_j)$ $A_{\pi(j)}$ is the sorted vector = ${x_{\pi(1)}, x_{\pi(2)}, &amp;hellip;}$ $g$ is the learned measure (subsumes LOS, OWA, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilayer Perceptrons are the basic unit of a NN</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/multilayer-perceptrons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/multilayer-perceptrons/</guid>
      <description>A type of NN that implements multiple layers of the [[Perceptron]].
$\mathbf{x}$ = input vector of length $N$
$\mathbf{w}$ = weight vector of length $N$
$\sigma$ = activation function (typically ReLU, tanh, sigmoid, etc.)
$y$ = output scalar
$\hat{y}$ = label scalar
$e$ = error or loss scalar function (typically 1/2e^2)
$$ y = \sigma(w^T \cdot x) $$ $$ e = \frac{1}{2}(\hat{y} - y)^2$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks (NNs) approximate any function</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>Neural networks are universal function approximators, according to the Universal function approximation theorem. [[multilayer perceptrons]]. Neural Networks eventually got deeper and more sophisticated, becoming the single most useful tool for artificial intelligence.
Activation Functions ReLU TanH Sigmoid Loss Functions (1/2)e^2 Softmax $$ \sigma(z)i = \frac{\exp{z_i}}{\Sigma{j=1}^K \exp{z_j}} $$ $z$ is the input vector, $\in {-\infty,\infty}$, can be pos, neg, zero. $\exp{z}$ is applied to each element of the input vector, gives a pos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Flavor, 99 Calories</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/full-flavor-99-calories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/blog/full-flavor-99-calories/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to check, we might be out of Bud Select today, what do you want instead —- Bud Light?&amp;rdquo; No, you can&amp;rsquo;t replace the best type of Bud&amp;hellip;
It seems so impossible before it happens. You see it approaching. You see all of the warning signs, all of the speed bumps preparing you for the abrupt stop ahead. Somber stories are repeated from old friends who are long past the days of sitting on rooftops at 2pm on a Tuesday, skipping class and drinking cold ones out of a squat, plastic cup, deciding that their responsibilities can be pushed off for at least two more hours, until they hit that Ballmer peak of &amp;ldquo;creativity&amp;rdquo; or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to call drunkenly typing meandering lines of thought and utilizing spell check way too much and re-doing it all the next morning anyway &amp;ndash; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
