<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Blake Ruprecht</title>
    <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Blake Ruprecht</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>/notes</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/notes/</guid>
      <description>Simple living is the goal.
After all,
If minimum wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the minimum.
Col. Brian Whetstone, U.S.M.C.
sleep hygiene nutrition exercise tools and home </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>exercise</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/exercise/</guid>
      <description>Summary Focus on proper technique for all movement, from breathing and standing, to running and lifting. Build strength thru training pushing, pulling, and squatting movements. Train Zone 2 cardio a lot each week. Train Zone 4/5 cardio some each week.
Physiological Adaptations of the Body to Exercise [1] Anaerobic endurance: max heart rate, how much work you can do at max effort Aerobic endurance: bodies ability to efficiently use oxygen during exercise Long-duration endurance: how long your body can perform sub-maximal work Technique: learning to move more effectively, efficiently, smoothly, and reducing risk of injury Muscular Endurance: how many reps in a row you can do Strength: how effectively you can move something Speed: moving at a higher velocity or with more accelaration Power: speed multiplied by force Size: how big the muscle is Training Pillars [2] Stability Proper technique in all things, this is the most complicated topic here by far, it&amp;rsquo;s basically &amp;ldquo;good form&amp;rdquo;, which changes from exercise to exercise, and needs to be evaluated for each joint and each muscle individually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hygiene</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/hygiene/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/hygiene/</guid>
      <description>A note on taking a random person&amp;rsquo;s medical advice: don&amp;rsquo;t So much related to general health and hygiene should come from your personal doctors who gives you checkups, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much more advice to give, besides listen to the professionals. Sure, some of them are in the pockets of big-pharma, but for the most part, they have good advice. Get a second opinion if you want, but this is not really the area to &amp;ldquo;do your own research&amp;rdquo;, since the field of medicine is legitimately insanely complex and difficult to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nutrition</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Eat as much energy as you burn, roughly Food is energy for the body. Without enough energy, the body will slowly starve, leading to early death. With too much energy, the body will store the excess as body fat. Excess amounts of body fat can lead to many serious health problems, including early death. Neither of these are recommended. However, there is a range of weight for any given person in which they can be perfectly healthy, and any minor differences within that range have nothing to do with nutrition, so that discussion falls outside the scope of these notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sleep</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/sleep/</guid>
      <description>General notes Notes from Huberman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Toolkit for Sleep&amp;rdquo;
Most humans need anywhere from 6-9 hours per night, you can tell based on if you are tired the next day lol Ideally, sleep in a dark place Temperature should be cool, regulate temp with multiples layers e.g. blankets It&amp;rsquo;s more important to keep wakeup time consistent, and sleep whenever you get tired at night Light Sunlight immediately upon waking for 10-30 mins is hugely beneficial Don&amp;rsquo;t look directly at the sun obviously, but don&amp;rsquo;t wear sunglasses, and windows block sunlight Avoid artifical light after dark if possible, if not, block blue light after dark Blue light keeps you awake during the day, so don&amp;rsquo;t block it during daytime Viewing sunlight in the evening is beneficial as well Bright lights between 10 p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tools and home</title>
      <link>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/tools-and-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blakeruprecht.github.io/notes/tools-and-home/</guid>
      <description> Clothes Work backpack Ultralight hiking backpack Bicycle Car (if no public transportation is available) Home Kitchen Living area Bed Bathroom </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
